Leave no man behind.
Black Hawk Down is a action, war, history film directed by Ridley Scott.
Rangers and an elite Delta Force team attempt to kidnap two underlings of a Somali warlord, their Black Hawk helicopters are
shot down, and the Americans suffer heavy casualties, facing intense fighting from the militia on the ground.
SSG Matthew Eversmann, played by Josh Hartnett.
SFC Norm 'Hoot' Gibson, played by Eric Bana.
SPC John Grimes, played by Ewan McGregor.
LTC Danny McKnight, played by Tom Sizemore.
SFC Jeff Sanderson, played by William Fichtner.
MG William F. Garrison, played by Sam Shepard.
Black Hawk Down is a 2001 war film directed and produced by Ridley Scott, and
co-produced by Jerry Bruckheimer, from a screenplay by Ken Nolan.
It is based on the 1999 eponymous non-fiction book by journalist Mark Bowden, about the crew
of a Black Hawk helicopter that was shot down during the Battle of Mogadishu.
The film features a large ensemble cast, including Josh Hartnett, Ewan McGregor, Eric Bana, Tom Sizemore, William Fichtner, Jason
Isaacs, Sam Shepard, Jeremy Piven, Ioan Gruffudd, Ewen Bremner, Hugh Dancy, and Tom Hardy in his first film role.
Orlando Bloom, Ty Burrell, and Nikolaj Coster-Waldau also have minor roles.
Black Hawk Down was produced by Columbia Pictures, Revolution Studios, Jerry Bruckheimer Films and Scott Free Productions and distributed
by Sony Pictures Releasing, and had a limited release on December 28, 2001, and went into the public on January 18, 2002.
The film received positive reviews from film critics,
although it was criticized for inaccuracies.
It performed modestly well at the box office, grossing $172 million
worldwide against a production budget of $92 million.
Black Hawk Down won two Academy Awards for Best Film Editing
and Best Sound at the 74th Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
ambush, chaos, militia, prisoner of war.
The tone is intense.